<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Javier</title><link>https://javier-luo.github.io</link><description>Medics,English</description><copyright>Javier</copyright><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><image><url>https://tgimg-dfe.pages.dev/file/AgACAgUAAyEGAASY6BlGAAMMaGRclk3iStA-o9Ve4LcUnSumRmQAAoLLMRtMkChX0G22A5bcAqUBAAMCAAN3AAM2BA.jpg</url><title>avatar</title><link>https://javier-luo.github.io</link></image><lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 22:42:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><managingEditor>Javier</managingEditor><ttl>60</ttl><webMaster>Javier</webMaster><item><title>考研英语2008 Text 3</title><link>https://javier-luo.github.io/post/kao-yan-ying-yu-2008%20Text%203.html</link><description>①In the early 1960s Wilt Chamberlain was one of the only three players in the National Basketball Association (NBA) listed at over seven feet. If he had played last season, however, he would have been one of 42. The bodies playing major professional sports have changed dramatically over the years, and managers have  been more than willing to adjust team uniforms to fit the growing numbers of bigger, longer frames.
20 世纪 60 年代初，威尔特·张伯伦是被列入全国篮球协会（NBA）超过七英尺的仅有三名球员之一。</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://javier-luo.github.io/post/kao-yan-ying-yu-2008%20Text%203.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 22:41:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>考研英语2008 Text 2</title><link>https://javier-luo.github.io/post/kao-yan-ying-yu-2008%20Text%202.html</link><description>①It used to be so straightforward. A team of researchers working together in the laboratory would submit the results of their research to a journal. A journal editor would then remove the authors’ names and affiliations from the paper and send it to their peers for review. Depending on the comments received, the editor would accept the paper for publication or decline it. Copyright rested with the journal publisher,  and researchers seeking knowledge of the results would have to subscribe to the journal.
它曾是如此直接。</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://javier-luo.github.io/post/kao-yan-ying-yu-2008%20Text%202.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 22:36:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>考研英语2008 Text 1</title><link>https://javier-luo.github.io/post/kao-yan-ying-yu-2008%20Text%201.html</link><description>①While still catching up to men in some spheres of modern life, women appear to be way ahead in at least one undesirable category. “Women are particularly susceptible to developing depression and anxiety disorders in response to stress compared to men,” according to Dr. Yehuda, chief psychiatrist at New York’s Veteran’s Administration Hospital.
尽管女性在现代生活中的不少领城仍在努力追赶男性，但至少在一个不利的方面女性似乎遥遥领先。</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://javier-luo.github.io/post/kao-yan-ying-yu-2008%20Text%201.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 00:10:24 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>考研英语2007 Text 4</title><link>https://javier-luo.github.io/post/kao-yan-ying-yu-2007%20Text%204.html</link><description>①It never rains but it pours. Just as bosses and boards have finally sorted out their worst accounting and compliance troubles, and improved their feeble corporation governance, a new problem threatens to earn them——especially in America——the  sort of nasty headlines that inevitably lead to heads rolling in the executive suite: data insecurity. Left, until now, to odd, low-level IT staff to put right, and seen as a concern only of data-rich industries such as banking, telecoms and air travel, information protection is now high on the boss’ s agenda in businesses of every variety.
不雨则已，雨则倾盆。</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://javier-luo.github.io/post/kao-yan-ying-yu-2007%20Text%204.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 00:04:10 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>考研英语2007 Text 3</title><link>https://javier-luo.github.io/post/kao-yan-ying-yu-2007%20Text%203.html</link><description>①During the past generation, the American middle-class family that once could count on hard work and fair play to keep itself financially secure has been  transformed by economic risk and new realities. Now a pink slip, a bad diagnosis, or  a disappearing spouse can reduce a family from solidly middle class to newly poor in a few months.
在过去一代人的时间里，原本依靠努力工作和公乎竞争便能保持自身经济安稳的美国中产阶级家庭已被经济风险和新的现实彻底改变现在，一张粉色小纸条（解雇通知书），一个恶性诊断结果，或者离散的配偶，都可以使一个家庭从殷实的中产阶级在几个月内沧为新贫阶层。</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://javier-luo.github.io/post/kao-yan-ying-yu-2007%20Text%203.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2025 23:57:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>考研英语2007 Text 2</title><link>https://javier-luo.github.io/post/kao-yan-ying-yu-2007%20Text%202.html</link><description>①For the past several years, the Sunday newspaper supplement _Parade_ has featured a column called “Ask Marilyn.” People are invited to query Marilyn vos Savant, who at age 10 had tested at a mental level of someone about 23 years old; that gave her an IQ of 228 – the highest score ever recorded. IQ tests ask you to complete verbal and visual analogies, to envision paper after it has been folded and cut, and to deduce numerical sequences, among other similar tasks. So it is a bit confusing when vos Savant fields such queries from the average Joe (whose IQ is 100) as, What’s the difference between love and fondness? Or what is the nature of luck and coincidence? It’ s not obvious how the capacity to visualize objects and to figure out numerical patterns suits one to answer questions that have eluded some of the best poets and philosophers.
在过去几年中，报纸周日副刊《大观》开设了一版名为“问问玛丽莲”的特色专栏。</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://javier-luo.github.io/post/kao-yan-ying-yu-2007%20Text%202.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2025 23:50:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>考研英语2007 Text 1</title><link>https://javier-luo.github.io/post/kao-yan-ying-yu-2007%20Text%201.html</link><description>①If you were to examine the birth certificates of every soccer player in 2006’s World Cup tournament, you would most likely find a noteworthy quirk: elite soccer players are more likely to have been born in the earlier months of the year than in the later months. If you then examined the European national youth teams that feed the World Cup and professional ranks, you would find this strange phenomenon to be even more pronounced.
如果查看一下 2006 年世界杯赛所有足球运动员的出生证，你很可能会发现一件引人注意的奇事：出类拔萃的足球运动员更可能出生在一年中的头几个月而非后几个月。</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://javier-luo.github.io/post/kao-yan-ying-yu-2007%20Text%201.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2025 23:45:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>考研英语2006 Text 4</title><link>https://javier-luo.github.io/post/kao-yan-ying-yu-2006%20Text%204.html</link><description>①Many things make people think artists are weird. But the weirdest may be this: artists’ only job is to explore emotions, and yet they choose to focus on the ones that feel bad.
许多事情使人们认为艺术家是怪异的。</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://javier-luo.github.io/post/kao-yan-ying-yu-2006%20Text%204.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2025 23:36:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>考研英语2006 Text 3</title><link>https://javier-luo.github.io/post/kao-yan-ying-yu-2006%20Text%203.html</link><description>①When prehistoric man arrived in new parts of the world, something strange happened to the large animals: they suddenly became extinct. Smaller species survived. The large, slow-growing animals were easy game, and were quickly hunted to extinction. Now something similar could be happening in the oceans.
当史前人类到达世界的新区域时，某些奇怪的事情发生在大型动物身上：它们突然灭绝了。</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://javier-luo.github.io/post/kao-yan-ying-yu-2006%20Text%203.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2025 23:27:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>考研英语2006 Text 2</title><link>https://javier-luo.github.io/post/kao-yan-ying-yu-2006%20Text%202.html</link><description>①Stratford-on-Avon, as we all know, has only one industry  –  William Shakespeare – but there are two distinctly separate and increasingly hostile branches. There is the Royal Shakespeare Company (RSC), which presents superb productions of the plays at the Shakespeare Memorial Theatre on the Avon. And there are the townsfolk who largely live off the tourists who come, not to see the plays, but to look at Anne Hathaway’s Cottage, Shakespeare’s birthplace and the other sights.
众所周知，埃文河畔的斯特拉特福德镇只有一个产业——威廉·莎士比亚，却有两个泾渭分明且日益敌对的派别。</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://javier-luo.github.io/post/kao-yan-ying-yu-2006%20Text%202.html</guid><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2025 23:21:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>考研英语2006 Text 1</title><link>https://javier-luo.github.io/post/kao-yan-ying-yu-2006%20Text%201.html</link><description>①In spite of “endless talk of difference,” American society is an amazing machine for homogenizing people. There is “the democratizing uniformity of dress and discourse, and the casualness and absence of deference” characteristic of popular culture. People are absorbed into “a culture of consumption” launched by the 19th-century department stores that offered “vast arrays of goods in an elegant atmosphere. Instead of intimate shops catering to a knowledgeable elite” these were stores “anyone could enter, regardless of class or background. This turned shopping into a public and democratic act.” The mass media, advertising and sports are other forces for homogenization.
尽管“无休止地谈论差异”，美国社会却是一部使人们同化的惊人机器。</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://javier-luo.github.io/post/kao-yan-ying-yu-2006%20Text%201.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 22:51:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>考研英语2005 Text 4</title><link>https://javier-luo.github.io/post/kao-yan-ying-yu-2005%20Text%204.html</link><description>①Americans no longer expect public figures, whether in speech or in writing, to command the English language with skill and gift. Nor do they aspire to such command themselves. In his latest book, _Doing Our Own Thing: The Degradation of Language and Music and Why We Should Like, Care_, John McWhorter, a linguist and controversialist of mixed liberal and conservative views, sees the triumph of 1960s counter-culture as responsible for the decline of formal English.
无论在演讲还是在写作上，美国人都不再期望公众人物在英语语言的使用上展现出技能与天赋：而公众人物自身也不渴求有这种语言驾驭能力。</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://javier-luo.github.io/post/kao-yan-ying-yu-2005%20Text%204.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 22:42:48 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>考研英语2005 Text 3</title><link>https://javier-luo.github.io/post/kao-yan-ying-yu-2005%20Text%203.html</link><description>①Of all the components of a good night’s sleep, dreams seem to be least within our control. In dreams, a window opens into a world where logic is suspended and dead people speak. A century ago, Freud formulated his revolutionary theory that dreams were the disguised shadows of our unconscious desires and fears; by the late 1970s, neurologists had switched to thinking of them as just “mental noise” – the random byproducts of the neural-repair work that goes on during sleep. Now researchers suspect that dreams are part of the mind’s emotional thermostat, regulating moods while the brain is “off-line.” And one leading authority says that these intensely powerful mental events can be not only harnessed but actually brought under conscious control, to help us sleep and feel better. “It’s your dream,” says Rosalind Cartwright, chair of psychology at Chicago’s Medical Center. “If you don’t like it, change it.”
在一夜好眠的所有因素中，梦似乎是最无法控制的。</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://javier-luo.github.io/post/kao-yan-ying-yu-2005%20Text%203.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 22:37:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>考研英语2005 Text 2</title><link>https://javier-luo.github.io/post/kao-yan-ying-yu-2005%20Text%202.html</link><description>①Do you remember all those years when scientists argued that smoking would kill us but the doubters insisted that we didn’t know for sure? That the evidence was inconclusive, the science uncertain? That the antismoking lobby was out to destroy our way of life and the government should stay out of the way? Lots of Americans bought that nonsense, and over three decades, some 10 million smokers went to early graves.
还记得那些年吗？科学家们提出吸烟会使我们丧命，而怀疑者们却坚称我们对此无法定论；他们坚称证据不确凿，科学不确定；他们坚称反对吸烟的游说者企图破坏我们的生活方式，而政府应该置身事外。</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://javier-luo.github.io/post/kao-yan-ying-yu-2005%20Text%202.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 15:01:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>考研英语2005 Text 1</title><link>https://javier-luo.github.io/post/kao-yan-ying-yu-2005%20Text%201.html</link><description>①Everybody loves a fat pay rise. Yet pleasure at your own can vanish if you learn that a colleague has been given a bigger one. Indeed, if he has a reputation for slacking, you might even be outraged. Such behaviour is regarded as “all too human”, with the underlying assumption that other animals would not be capable of this finely developed sense of grievance. But a study by Sarah Brosnan and Frans de Waal of Emory University in Atlanta, Georgia, which has just been published in _Nature_, suggests that &lt;u&gt;it is all too monkey&lt;/u&gt;, as well.
人人都爱丰厚加薪。</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://javier-luo.github.io/post/kao-yan-ying-yu-2005%20Text%201.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 14:52:35 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>